<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[My Startup Journey]]></title>
  <link href="dustincfox.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="dustincfox.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-05T17:36:19-05:00</updated>
  <id>dustincfox.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Little Bit About Me]]></title>
    <link href="dustincfox.com/blog/2014/04/03/first-post/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-03T16:58:55-05:00</updated>
    <id>dustincfox.com/blog/2014/04/03/first-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This first post is to give a quick background of how I got to the place where I am looking for my first developer job.  I will go into more depth on some of these topics in future posts.</p>

<p>I grew up with a love of technology from a very young age.  In high school I started my first computer programming course in C++.  I continued to take programming classes througout high school and decided that I wanted to go into computer engineering for college.  College was not easy for me.  In high school I barely had to try to get good grades and as a consequence I never developed strong studying skills. That plus my hatred for the inefficiencies of the school system lead to me slipping more and more as the years went on. Eventually I found myself failing out of my degree program with no idea how to turn it around.  I decided that I was going to move on and get what job I could find and switch schools and majors to complete my education.  As you might imagine, this just led to me bouncing around from program to program and job to job always searching and never being happy.</p>

<p>Eventually I got fed up with that cycle and decided I was going to really figure out what I wanted to do and do it.  That led me to my first Startup Weekend.  For those not familiar, Startup Weekend is an organization that holds a weekend long competition where about 100 people come together and split into teams and create a business pitch around a minimum viable prodcut in a matter of 54 hours.  From the moment that weekend got started, I was enamoured.  I just couldn&rsquo;t get enough of this &lsquo;startup life&rsquo; and so I set out on a journey to figure out how I could make that a career.</p>

<p>What I found during my search was two fold.  Firstly, there was not a thriving startup scene in the small midwestern town that I was living in.  And secondly, my skillset was not easily definable and therefore it was hard to pitch why any startup should hire me.  In trying to overcome those obstacles my wife and I move to Chicago which has a great startup scene.  I knew that because of all the opportunities in this great city, I would be working at the company of my dreams in no time.  This was not the case, however.  I figured that my mix of technical knowledge and business acumen would be plenty for a company to take a chance on me.  What I found out is that it was very hard to define any one thing that I could immediately contribute and therefore I would have to give a hard sell pitch in order to even get an audience. Because I knew that I really wanted to a part of a startup, I decided that I needed to get a definable skill. That search led me to Dev Bootcamp which is a 9 week intensive bootcamp where students spend 60 &ndash; 80 hours a week learning how to build websites.</p>

<p>That is where my story begins.  I hope that this blog will help others that are struggling with the same issues that I struggled with find their path.</p>

<p>Thanks for reading!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
